<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mike Hartington</title>
    <link>https://mhartington.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mike Hartington</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 16:15:09 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mhartington.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ionic Colors Map: How to use them correctly</title>
      <link>https://mhartington.io/post/ionic-colors-map/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2017 16:15:09 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mhartington.io/post/ionic-colors-map/</guid>
      <description>If you jumped from Ionic 1 to Ionic 2 when it was first released, a new thing that was added was this concept of $colors. Something that looks like this :
$colors: ( primary: #488aff, secondary: #32db64, danger: #f53d3d, light: #f4f4f4, dark: #222 );  This was a big change from how we did styles in Ionic 1, where all of our theme colors were defined upfront:
$light: #fff !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPhoneX and The Notch</title>
      <link>https://mhartington.io/post/iphonex-and-the-notch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 10:39:55 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mhartington.io/post/iphonex-and-the-notch/</guid>
      <description>Every year Apple releases a new iPhone and a new iOS version to match. For the history of the iPhone, any changes that come with these new devices tend to be very small. Design changes in iOS7? Not a huge deal, as they&amp;rsquo;re fairly easy to design for, especially in a hybrid app context. This year however, Apple has introduce it&amp;rsquo;s most drastic change in iPhone history.
Introducing… the Notch</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Decorators</title>
      <link>https://mhartington.io/post/custom-decorators/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2017 09:55:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mhartington.io/post/custom-decorators/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been getting more into decorators lately, especially since I used them in Angular/Ionic, but also in Python. But I realized that I really didn&amp;rsquo;t know much about them or how they actually worked. So I spent some time last night and built a small decorator, @platformReady().
WTH is a decorators Decorators can get confusing real fast, so we&amp;rsquo;re going to try to stay pretty high level here. In its simplest form, a decorator allows developers to perform higher-level functions on an annotated class or method.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revisiting Typings: Post 1.0</title>
      <link>https://mhartington.io/post/typings-v1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2016 13:03:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mhartington.io/post/typings-v1/</guid>
      <description>Typings hits 1.0! Typings finally hit its 1.0 recently (well more like a month or so ago), and with this it brought some drastic change to the API. So my previous post is now out of date. This is a perfect chance to go over these changes and how it may affect your project.
What&amp;rsquo;s new? So a simple overview what&amp;rsquo;s changed from 0.X to 1.X has been provided in the README.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ionic 2 and External Libraries</title>
      <link>https://mhartington.io/post/ionic2-external-libraries/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2016 11:38:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mhartington.io/post/ionic2-external-libraries/</guid>
      <description>Now that Ionic 2 is out in beta, people are setting aside some time to give it a shot and investigate everything it has to offer. Ionic 2 and Angular 2 bring a lot of improvements, but it&amp;rsquo;s a fairly different style of developing that what people were used to before. Now, since everything needs to be imported and libraries aren’t global, it can be tricky to figure out how to integrate with other libraries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Focus to an Input in Ionic 2</title>
      <link>https://mhartington.io/post/setting-input-focus/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Feb 2016 09:37:41 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mhartington.io/post/setting-input-focus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A Question came up in the Ionic Worldwide Slack today about how to set focus to an input. Now normally you&amp;rsquo;d think you would be able to call &lt;code&gt;.focus()&lt;/code&gt; and call it day. But Ionic wraps native text inputs with custom Angular 2 components to better control the user experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Object Fit</title>
      <link>https://mhartington.io/post/object-fit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 20:54:55 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mhartington.io/post/object-fit/</guid>
      <description>Today I was watching a random video on ES6 tooling when I saw the author use a CSS property I&amp;rsquo;d never heard of. object-fit, and it was pretty awesome.
 Method of specifying how an object (image or video) should fit inside its box. object-fit options include &amp;ldquo;contain&amp;rdquo; (fit according to aspect ratio), &amp;ldquo;fill&amp;rdquo; (stretches object to fill) and &amp;ldquo;cover&amp;rdquo; (overflows box but maintains ratio), where object-position allows the object to be repositioned like background-image does.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ionic IO app name</title>
      <link>https://mhartington.io/post/ionic-io-app-name/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2016 16:01:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mhartington.io/post/ionic-io-app-name/</guid>
      <description>A good question came up in the Ionic Slack today. A dev was looking to change the name of an app that was already uploaded to the Ionic platform portal.
When you start an ionic project from the CLI, along with all the html/css/js that you need, it creats an ionic.project file. In here, you get your apps name and app_id set, which gets used by the CLI
{ &amp;quot;name&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;tmp&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;app_id&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;9cf2c890&amp;quot; }  Now when I login to the Platform portal and upload my app, I&amp;rsquo;ll see it appear on my dash.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Year</title>
      <link>https://mhartington.io/post/a-new-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2016 12:09:03 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mhartington.io/post/a-new-year/</guid>
      <description>This isn&amp;rsquo;t as much as a year in review for 2015, but all the things I look forward to doing in 2016.
2015 So 2015 was a big year for me. I gave so many talks and got to meet a whole bunch of other speakers. This was definitly a year where I felt like I grew the most as a speaker and developer. If you&amp;rsquo;re looking to become a better speaker or get into being a dev advocate, defintily checkout this talk by Ben Orenstein</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Dotfiles</title>
      <link>https://mhartington.io/post/my-dotfiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2015 10:30:41 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mhartington.io/post/my-dotfiles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My dotfiles are my pride and joy. There are hundreds of hours spent tweaking them to create the best setup for me. Recently I&amp;rsquo;ve started working on three different machines, my Mac, a Windows machine, as well as Ubuntu. This introduced an interesting issue; how can I create a similar environment across all these platforms, but only store them in one location?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>https://mhartington.io/post/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2015 09:37:11 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mhartington.io/post/welcome/</guid>
      <description>Consider this my first post</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>